<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TimmyStream!</title>
    <description>Basically parts of the brain of audio/visual creative, restless dabbler, an intentional wanderer, and jack-of-all-trades of some sort that goes by the name Timothy Diokno. Ramblings, musings, random things of interest, online landing page, and creative sandbox.
</description>
    <link>http://tsdiokno.github,io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://tsdiokno.github,io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2015 16:57:39 +0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2015 16:57:39 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Can't Fake It Till You Make It.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Was for a Facebook post. It got long and I wanted to practice Vim. An extensive commentary (as I would always get in to) to &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/1562350/copy-and-paste-from-external-source&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re not justifying sin. Sin must be repented of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we don’t fake change, either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don’t put the cart before the horse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Change starts from within.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We begin with practicality. When you’re practical, you must be thinking right most of the time. Therefore, you’re wise, because you embrace wisdom. And wisdom is good. And God is good and all truth and good comes from God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe “Biblicalism” is a highly practical way of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Observe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We stop swearing&lt;/em&gt; because there are better ways of strongly expressing oneself. We should express with self control and consideration to the people around us. (Hold up. Saying this, this hurt me tremendously first before it ever might have ticked something in you. No excuses here.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We stop adding more tattoos&lt;/em&gt; to our bodies (if we already have one) because it might be aesthetically unsound (subjective) and tattoos are known to contaminate blood (pretty objective). And, of course, to consider that we are part of a society that still has a stigma against tattoos. We have to take things slow, sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We stop constantly getting drunk&lt;/em&gt; because it’s bad for our liver (and our bellies, if you’re in to beer) and we usually end up using it to justify a lot of the bad things we do while we’re drunk. When, actually, “drunk” sins have little to do with the drink and more to do with your mind while drinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We stop insulting people and being mean&lt;/em&gt; because it makes them uncomfortable and, depending on the receiving end, it would breed discord, disorder, and a lot of things that define a dysfunctional society. And it’s wrong and selfish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We stop smoking&lt;/em&gt; because not everybody wants the smell of smoke. And not everybody wants to die along with you when your lungs give in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We don’t engage in pre-marital sex&lt;/em&gt; because if we do it, human relationships unnecessarily get complicated. Hard sell? Be our guest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We stop being arrogant and disrespectful&lt;/em&gt; because we really don’t know everything in life. And when we become so full of it, we only hasten our own undoing and be left with no one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We stop emulating Jacka**&lt;/em&gt; in all levels because God made you for better things in life. And when you spend most of your time trying to have fun hurting and/or humiliating yourself consequently (or both at the same time), you miss out on doing better things for humanity in the name of Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And Jesus certainly didn’t save you to hurt yourself or others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He saved you, first, so that you could give glory to Him..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And I don’t think you’d be exactly doing it through being a total Jacka**.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://tsdiokno.github,io/2015/08/21/makefake.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tsdiokno.github,io/2015/08/21/makefake.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Oh, Ain't this Cool?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So, I’m trying out this thingamabob called Jekyll because I just thought it’s kinda fun. Nothing much really. Just the usual dabbling with stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pretty stoked about what I’ll be able to do with this thing, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is neat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additional cool stuff aside from this is I’m also doing this with Vim – again, just because it’s fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been forever since I wanted to start to try and go about things like this and, hey!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, this would be the first file, I guess. I’m just practicing and trying to figure my way around Vim. And it’s true, you gotta really get a hang of it. Though running it in Linux (Ubuntu), I think, definitely helped because everything feels a bit more natural, I don’t really know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But again, hey. Stay tuned for stuff I’ll be putting out here. Lots of randomness and lots of things breaking because I’ll be fiddling with this more in the following days (not with not already rolling-in content from time to time).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers!
T&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2015 07:38:10 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://tsdiokno.github,io/jekyll/update/2015/08/20/yellowworld.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tsdiokno.github,io/jekyll/update/2015/08/20/yellowworld.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
