<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TimmyStream!</title>
    <description>Basically parts of the brain of audio/visual creative, restless dabbler, an intentional wanderer, and jack-of-all-trades of some sort that goes by the name Timothy Diokno. Ramblings, musings, random things of interest, online landing page, and creative sandbox.
</description>
    <link>http://tsdiokno.github,io/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://tsdiokno.github,io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2015 00:36:05 +0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2015 00:36:05 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Personal Quick And Dirty Wise Voting Strategy</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Now that I have been officially a registered voter, I now have this so-called power to effect change to the country by shading hollow shapes on a sheet of paper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But not everyone thinks of it that way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You know… the “changing the country” bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everybody in The Philippins have probably already heard of different reasons why some people would leave the comfort of their homes, fall in line outside of their precint, pen some marks down, drop a piece of paper called a “ballot”, and go about life whether towards a hopeful anticipation, or to life as we know it typically.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We vote for money. Vote buying. Paying people to vote for somebody just because it puts food on their table or buys them an extra venti Frapuccino on their next hangout with some friends.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We vote because we have to. Routinary. It’s not a “power” per se, voting. It’s like filing taxes, only less complex and it happens on huge intervals.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;We vote, perhaps, we’re that just crazy enough to believe that the ballot can still make things better.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then there’s the reason of our choices themselves. Why do we root for whom we’d root for?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Because I’ve been hearing about this guy everywhere.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And he (or she) is the only one you might actually know (not along with a few more) on that long list of names. And you gotta shade one. It makes no sense to a certan extent to root for somebody that you haven’t heard of before that the idea makes it the worst type of gambling in humanity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Because he’s been kind to us. He did a lot for us.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And he might have smiled, talked, hugged, and have personally gone to your place, too. Why wouldn’t you vote for such a guy in a country wherein almost everybody on post is, if not busy laying back in their posts, are somewhere else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s probably more but these are the things that I could only think of for now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m voting. But I’m hoping to extend those reasons (if you’d ever echo them have you been participating on elections).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;we-need-effective-leaders----not-just-popular-ones&quot;&gt;We Need Effective Leaders – Not Just Popular Ones.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It has been said that there is “power in numbers”. But it has also been said that these numbers wouldn’t actually reflect anything commendable. Because they just tell one story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They just determine a popular eligible, but not necessarily the most effective ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;You want people who can effect change on the things that you think everybody ought to care about.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I agree with the thought that a good leader, a good alpha-mojojo, or whatever you wanna call it, should have a heavy charisma because no leader can lead by being doormats and basically nobodies – but that’s just part of why I think we should choose a candidate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;two-simple-questions-to-a-good-pick&quot;&gt;Two Simple Questions To A Good Pick.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this ramble, I’ll try to list down my personal process for trying to make the best informed decisions that I can make during the elections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Studying a candidate’s background personally, one-by-one, doesn’t work for me since I’m not really inclined in to becoming a lay political analyst. And I’d belive The People would also want to spend more time on other things that they deem more valuable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s my current personal approach on choosing who to vote for.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d ask myself the following questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;does-he-push-for-the-things-that-i-would-personally-want-to-push-for&quot;&gt;1. Does he push for the things that I would personally want to push for?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pretty easy. If the candidate has been a legislator, check out Bills and Resolutions he’d support or co-write. If he pushes for something that you might specially care about, that’s a candidate to consider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Internet, of course, is the best place to start looking for these things. And it might sound funny but you should go and check out your prospect’s official website and they are usually more than happy to have presented a section dedicated for such information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;does-this-guy-show-up-and-get-things-done&quot;&gt;2. Does this guy show up and get things done?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the candidate has also been on executive positions, check if the candidate would have delivered tangible results within his term. Were his projects really helpful – even for the long run? Being a government official isn’t easy but you’ll know somebody who gets things done when you see it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does your candidate get anything done? Has it been done well? Were the objectives of their projects valid? Would it help people in their key needs? Was he able to move his people in to action?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s the Internet, then there’s the &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; Internet. Whereas choosing a legislator for a legislative position would usually require me to simply be in agreement with a prospect’s way of thinking and principles, tangibility of results would matter more when it comes to picking an executive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, how are you going to do that?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You can check for the volume of validly-purposed local infrastructure. Are the roads smooth, are the streets of the locality well-equipped with pedestrian aides, are the street lights even working, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;blockquote&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;“But that’s not just for the local government unit to work on. That’s what bureaus and departments are for!”&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/blockquote&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;And I think it’s the local government’s job to make sure the needs of their constituents are being fulfilled. A better offical wouldn’t always take a “no/wait” for an answer and abruptly cease aspiring for the best of his constituents.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You can check for how disciplined the people would become. The followers might just be as bad (or good) as their leader. For the most part, the basic understanding would be that the duty to turn legislation in to execution is an executive, of course. Is there discipline? Are regulations and guidelines being enforced faithfully and adhered to?&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;I’d figure, if this guy can make things happen when he hasn’t made the cut yet, perhaps it’s not that far-fetched to think he’d do the same well he &lt;em&gt;does&lt;/em&gt; make it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-fast-no-fuzz-way-of-choosing-candidates&quot;&gt;A Fast, No-Fuzz Way Of Choosing Candidates.&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that’s pretty much it, actually. No fuzz.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some people would rather go further in to bit by digging deeper in to the tendencies, background, or the inclination of a person, but I think the things that I would’ve listed are just a few things if not everything that matters in choosing somebody to lead and produce results.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://tsdiokno.github,io/2015/08/22/phelections2016.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tsdiokno.github,io/2015/08/22/phelections2016.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>git pushmoteh</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Alright. More stuff to practice Vim with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I’m back to coding stuff again and I work with Git, I also bring back my aliases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stuff that I’d actually use at work in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Actually, for a good one, I just (vaguely) remember using one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enjoy! (I hope.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;git config --global alias.pushmoteh 'push origin master'&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://tsdiokno.github,io/2015/08/21/pushmoteh.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tsdiokno.github,io/2015/08/21/pushmoteh.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>On Authority, Democracy, Etc.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Not an anarchist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everybody needs authority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What everybody should hate, however, is not authority or the concept thereof.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We should hate authorities crossing lines and boundaries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We should hate totalitarianism… dictatorship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authorities exist to promote peace and order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They don’t and should not exist to enforce their personal biases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They don’t have any right to deny us our basic human rights just because.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They don’t have any right to deny us, the individuals, the excercise of our individuality and suffocate our free will to the point of internal death.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not that the individual is perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But neither is the individual a puppet… a machine that only does what a commanding agent tells it to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A word for all authorities of all sorts: don’t let it get to your head or we’ll chase it out of there.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We all have the capacity to think and to reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Democracy is messy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we shouldn’t have it any other way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give the society a chance to celebrate the realization and successes of their percepts or the chance to learn from mistakes arising from such.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let the babes walk on their own, fall on their own, and get up on their own; and savor the rewards of their realizations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Control is a part of it – but not &lt;em&gt;it&lt;/em&gt;!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We ought to &lt;em&gt;“take the highway”&lt;/em&gt; if we would be constantly given the option to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At least, in highways, we have the choice whether to go north or south, east or west – and let everybody realize and decide on both the best and the worst paths to take.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to dictate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s easy to say &lt;em&gt;“because I said so”.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it’s easy to shoot down dissentors and critics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because democracy demands empathy, patience, understanding. The genuine forms thereof not only demand a clean ear canal but also a clear motive, and an unclouded ego.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Democracy is the long road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Democracy is a slow cook.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Democracy is imperfect – and that’s what makes it perfect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nature is, in itself, imperfect – but not really so, &lt;em&gt;is it?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don’t follow whom we don’t trust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not that we don’t trust whatever it is that qualifies an authority.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In fact, we have an ample amount of trust on the whole beings of all authorities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That if the authorities think it to be true that their subjects are imperfect beings, capable of harm… of error (in other words: human), that they merit sanctions, control, rules, intervention, and the rightful implementation thereof through an agent of authority, the authorities merit the same in return.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the tendencies of authorities are no different from those of their subjects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Except the those tendencies are grately amplified when you are in power.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://tsdiokno.github,io/2015/08/21/marchmarchmarch.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tsdiokno.github,io/2015/08/21/marchmarchmarch.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Can't Fake It Till You Make It.</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Was for a Facebook post. It got long and I wanted to practice Vim. An extensive commentary (as I would always get in to) to &lt;a href=&quot;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/1562350/copy-and-paste-from-external-source&quot;&gt;this article&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re not justifying sin. Sin must be repented of.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But we don’t fake change, either.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We don’t put the cart before the horse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Change starts from within.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We begin with practicality. When you’re practical, you must be thinking right most of the time. Therefore, you’re wise, because you embrace wisdom. And wisdom is good. And God is good and all truth and good comes from God.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I believe “Biblicalism” is a highly practical way of life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Observe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We stop swearing&lt;/em&gt; because there are better ways of strongly expressing oneself. We should express with self control and consideration to the people around us. (Hold up. Saying this, this hurt me tremendously first before it ever might have ticked something in you. No excuses here.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We stop adding more tattoos&lt;/em&gt; to our bodies (if we already have one) because it might be aesthetically unsound (subjective) and tattoos are known to contaminate blood (pretty objective). And, of course, to consider that we are part of a society that still has a stigma against tattoos. We have to take things slow, sometimes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We stop constantly getting drunk&lt;/em&gt; because it’s bad for our liver (and our bellies, if you’re in to beer) and we usually end up using it to justify a lot of the bad things we do while we’re drunk. When, actually, “drunk” sins have little to do with the drink and more to do with your mind while drinking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We stop insulting people and being mean&lt;/em&gt; because it makes them uncomfortable and, depending on the receiving end, it would breed discord, disorder, and a lot of things that define a dysfunctional society. And it’s wrong and selfish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We stop smoking&lt;/em&gt; because not everybody wants the smell of smoke. And not everybody wants to die along with you when your lungs give in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We don’t engage in pre-marital sex&lt;/em&gt; because if we do it, human relationships unnecessarily get complicated. Hard sell? Be our guest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We stop being arrogant and disrespectful&lt;/em&gt; because we really don’t know everything in life. And when we become so full of it, we only hasten our own undoing and be left with no one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;We stop emulating Jacka**&lt;/em&gt; in all levels because God made you for better things in life. And when you spend most of your time trying to have fun hurting and/or humiliating yourself consequently (or both at the same time), you miss out on doing better things for humanity in the name of Jesus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And Jesus certainly didn’t save you to hurt yourself or others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He saved you, first, so that you could give glory to Him..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;And I don’t think you’d be exactly doing it through being a total Jacka**.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://tsdiokno.github,io/2015/08/21/makefake.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tsdiokno.github,io/2015/08/21/makefake.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Oh, Ain't this Cool?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;So, I’m trying out this thingamabob called Jekyll because I just thought it’s kinda fun. Nothing much really. Just the usual dabbling with stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pretty stoked about what I’ll be able to do with this thing, though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is neat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additional cool stuff aside from this is I’m also doing this with Vim – again, just because it’s fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been forever since I wanted to start to try and go about things like this and, hey!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, this would be the first file, I guess. I’m just practicing and trying to figure my way around Vim. And it’s true, you gotta really get a hang of it. Though running it in Linux (Ubuntu), I think, definitely helped because everything feels a bit more natural, I don’t really know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But again, hey. Stay tuned for stuff I’ll be putting out here. Lots of randomness and lots of things breaking because I’ll be fiddling with this more in the following days (not with not already rolling-in content from time to time).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers!
T&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2015 07:38:10 +0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://tsdiokno.github,io/jekyll/update/2015/08/20/yellowworld.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tsdiokno.github,io/jekyll/update/2015/08/20/yellowworld.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>jekyll</category>
        
        <category>update</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
